<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2019-02-26T18:00:00-06:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Pairing Tour — Day 08</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/gina-blog/2019/02/27/post22.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/gina-blog/2019/02/27/post22.html</id>
    <published>2019-02-26T18:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2020-02-01T13:39:52-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;main class="blogposts__container"&gt;
  &lt;header class="header-main"&gt;
    &lt;h1&gt;Pairing Tour — Day 08&lt;/h1&gt;
    &lt;time datetime="2019-02-27"&gt;February 27, 2019&lt;/time&gt;
  &lt;/header&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I continued pairing with Kelly Rauwerdink and Julia Murray to help on their client. The first half of the day was dedicated to our morning standup and tackling a new page with Kelly. This time, I was &lt;strong&gt;the driver&lt;/strong&gt; and Kelly was &lt;strong&gt;the navigator.&lt;/strong&gt; These terms refer to pair programming, which is common amongst software development teams. It’s when you have two team members working together on one screen or one coding program that allows for live code collaboration, such as Visual Studio Code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The driver&lt;/strong&gt; refers to the person working directly on the laptop, typing and using keyboard shortcuts, while &lt;strong&gt;the navigator&lt;/strong&gt; acts as guidance doing anything from directing with live feedback to quickly find answers via web search or sketch out possible solutions to experiment with that might be difficult to explain through words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We worked on a &lt;strong&gt;Ways to Give&lt;/strong&gt; page with a new approach: now that we had a more established visual style, we needed to identify reusable UI components. Kelly and I threw ideas at each other as far as what we could reuse or change slightly and from which pages. At first, what we were thinking did not completely work because we were still thinking of ways to break up the hierarchy of the page based off Julia’s low-fidelity wireframes. One of the problems that we were facing was that there were so many ways to give ranging from different topics: ways to donate, gift giving, and external giving through your workplace, financial institution, or even stock. Another issue that we faced was that generally speaking, there was a lot of content on the page that Julia had been working closely with the stakeholder to compromise and cut down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kelly and I talked through these problems, trying to figure out logical ways to break up these sections and reconsider where we grouped seemingly disparate pieces of sections, like tax forms or the client’s audit information. Some questions we asked ourselves: &lt;em&gt;Shouldn’t tax forms and the client audit information go with the different ways to donate because they were inherently related to donating? Are things like a gift acceptance policy or the donor bill of rights related to the act of donating, or are they closer related to the section where the organization provides legal proof that they are eligible and trustworthy in receiving donations?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We worked through the problem about halfway, reaching a point of headache, and a little frustration from fixating over smaller details. We decided it was a good stopping point to grab lunch, regroup, and then tackle that wireframe again. After regrouping and pairing with fresh eyes, we talked it through some more and made some progress before completely splitting up to cover more ground for the rest of the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a meeting with the ad agency team, which actually ended up running smoother because they had a project manager who was more accountable with note-taking and critical with her feedback. They gave Kelly edits to make, but fortunately, not as many as they did in the beginning when we were still trying to set the visual tone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following that meeting, I managed to finish the layout and create some iterations for Kelly’s review, but just as I was about to send them over, Julia came with new feedback—and with apologies because it was just bad luck that the edits happened to be for the page that Kelly and I had been slaving over for most of the day—from the client.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julia explained the feedback and shared the client’s rationale for the changes, all of which made perfect sense. Fortunately, the edits actually made the page better because the content was simplified, thereby allowing sections to arrange more harmoniously and intentionally. My day ended with making those edits from the client, creating possible iterations, and sending Kelly screenshots via Slack for feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/main&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Pairing Tour — Day 07</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/gina-blog/2019/02/26/post21.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/gina-blog/2019/02/26/post21.html</id>
    <published>2019-02-25T18:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2020-02-01T13:40:10-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;main class="blogposts__container"&gt;
  &lt;header class="header-main"&gt;
    &lt;h1&gt;Pairing Tour — Day 07&lt;/h1&gt;
    &lt;time datetime="2019-02-26"&gt;February 26, 2019&lt;/time&gt;
  &lt;/header&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, we had a change of plans today. My assigned mentor, Eva Penzeymoog, was feeling under the weather. In addition to being my mentor, Eva is a UX designer at 8th Light, an instructor who teaches UX at General Assembly, a proud feminist, and a career-driven woman in technology seeking to level up in her career through a new direction: giving conference talks on inclusive safety. Basically, she’s an all-around amazing human being both on and off the clock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once again I paired with Kyle Sparks, Kelly Rauwerdink, and Julia Murray. For my pairing with Kyle, we tackled together the codebase for 8th Light’s homepage, trying to take a wireframe that I created and convert a component into code. I started out flying solo in the morning because Kyle had a meeting. When we regrouped to discuss what I had done thus far, he came with a better new idea for our header image: what if we kept the video on our homepage but have that playing in the background with a faded color overlay and text on top?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my professional opinion, the video speaks more to what our company does, as well as brings a sense of humanity and warmth back to the cold, calculated perception of “custom software development” or “technology.” Navigating through stylesheets, code, and identifying pieces of code to repurpose and reuse took a little longer than expected, but together we managed to get it done in a reasonable timeframe. To finish it off, we made a pull request and opened it up for feedback from the design team, where Julia suggested to adjust the type weight for contrast, bump up the overlay, and consider type size for responsive design on desktop because it matched the rest of the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following my pairing with Kyle, I continued my work with Kelly and Julia, taking a new swing at laying out a high-fidelity UI wireframe based of Julia’s research and low-fidelity ones. I explored a possible layout for an &lt;strong&gt;About Us&lt;/strong&gt; page of this client’s website. As expected, my first swing was not the best. The difficulties posed by the color palette, the legibility of the text, and some of the pre-established styles supported a “boxy” layout, so I created other iterations and asked Kelly for feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By this point, we had a meeting with the ad agency team and had received more feedback and revisions, but this time, received a lot more positively because they seemed more engaged with the work. To finish off today, I received Kelly’s feedback, made her edits, and placed two versions of my high-fidelity wireframes up on our Trello workflow board.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/main&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Pairing Tour — Day 06</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/gina-blog/2019/02/25/post20.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/gina-blog/2019/02/25/post20.html</id>
    <published>2019-02-24T18:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2020-02-01T13:28:38-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;main class="blogposts__container"&gt;
  &lt;header class="header-main"&gt;
    &lt;h1&gt;Pairing Tour — Day 06&lt;/h1&gt;
    &lt;time datetime="2019-02-25"&gt;February 25, 2019&lt;/time&gt;
  &lt;/header&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I paired with Kevin Zolkiewicz, a designer at 8th Light who also happens to be a talented front-end developer. Kevin began our pairing day by introducing me to a merge conflict (thanks, Kevin). He and Alexa Albanese, another designer here at 8th Light, had been working on the same client for a few months now. With this client, they were working with contractors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The merge conflict that he showed me was from one of the contractors on the project, Jeneve, who focused on laying out some of the foundations of the front-end development to tackle more of the back-end. Kevin explained more about the code workflow, JavaScript and token, and React. He explained how they are pulling information from the database (back-end) to produce how the website is displayed using the awesome powers and convenience of React (front-end). He walked me through the merge conflict and resolved it by keeping both of the conflicts because they were lines of code created by him and Jeneve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was interesting to see how everything that I have learned during my apprenticeship applies in real-world context. Kevin explained how sites these days are actually now fully built using JavaScript as opposed to just HTML/CSS. The similarities and overlap between those languages was interesting because some of what I saw in the JavaScript file was very similar to using tokens or mixins in Sass, however, far more advanced than I would ever have to deal with or touch as a designer. He let me try using tokens and writing in the language a little before switching back over to figuring out how he would refactor some of Jeneve's rough layout of code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, we split up for part of our pairing. Reason being was because the implementation wasn't too engaging since I'm not familiar with the language he's working in.  Plus, it would give Kevin an opportunity to finish up his work, so that we could pair on something else. I had suggested that I could use some of this time to catch up on writing blog posts about my pairing tours since I was three days behind in terms of writing, so it worked out! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After refactoring some of Jeneve's code to be more manageable, Kevin went over the basics of ITSCSS and an introduction to programming by teaching me some basic JavaScript terminology: variables (booleans and strings), loops, conditionals, functions, operators, and briefly went over arrays. He figured that it would be nice just to help me familiarize with the language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/main&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Pairing Tour — Day 05</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/gina-blog/2019/02/22/post19.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/gina-blog/2019/02/22/post19.html</id>
    <published>2019-02-21T18:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2020-02-01T13:40:53-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;main class="blogposts__container"&gt;
  &lt;header class="header-main"&gt;
    &lt;h1&gt;Pairing Tour — Day 05&lt;/h1&gt;
    &lt;time datetime="2019-02-22"&gt;February 22, 2019&lt;/time&gt;
  &lt;/header&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I paired with Kyle Sparks, who is Communications Manager here at 8th Light. Kyle generally works on writing for internal requests, such as for proposals and presentations. He’s also very familiar with the GitHub workflow, along with coding skills in HTML, CSS, Ruby, and yaml.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pairing with Kyle is always enjoyable because he completes work with a sense of humor, lightheartedness, and professionalism. He came prepared this morning with a list of three things that he had coordinated on with Lydia Lindenberg, our Marketing Manager:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol class="blogpost--ol-indent"&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fix a simple social media link issue for 8th Light’s upcoming events on our website, so that when a site visitor clicked on “Facebook” or “Twitter,” they would be redirected to our company’s social accounts.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;Figure out possible layouts to address a specific section of our company’s homepage that displayed our services. According to research, users were unclear about what exactly our company does, despite having a section dedicated to what we do.&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;Add a section with a button on the company’s main blockchain services page that would direct users to the field guide download page.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;An additional but not absolutely necessary task that Kyle wanted to tackle was our company’s email design for the weekly bytes. We glazed over this point only as an introduction to some future work that Kyle might need help with.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kyle began our pairing by introducing me to the 8th Light codebase, which was way more familiar and manageable than the HubSpot workflow. He was careful and conscious about mansplaining, which I really appreciated, and made sure to let me know that I could interrupt him if I already knew something. He instructed me on some commands in terminal for cloning the repository and opening up in my text editor of choice: Visual Studio Code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were quick to fix the link issue and then moved on to addressing possible layouts for the section of the company’s homepage that would focus on our selling points. I worked in Sketch, ensuring to manage expectations and state that I cannot design and code at the same time. I created a few different wireframe layouts, attempting to stay consistent with our brand’s (informal) website style guide and referencing with Kyle what the other landing page headers look like. He seemed excited and interested in learning Sketch, where I suggested that I could teach him one of these days during waza, a brand specific term at our company that refers to a dedicated time slot to professional development, learning new skills, and/or working on side projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I finished the possible layouts in Sketch, we reached out to Lydia to ask for her feedback. At the time, she was in a meeting, so we then moved onto another task, which was creating the section with the button for the blockchain services landing page. Although this seemed simple, the challenge came with using the HubSpot interface, where related things feel so disconnected across the site in terms of the UX. The basic thing that Kyle and I had accomplished was placing the section and button underneath the header, but the problem was that the background color of that section was purple—so was the header.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem was trying to change that background to the lightest shade of gray in our style guide and change the text to be a darker shade of gray to match the rest of the brand. We had tackled it for roughly a half hour to no avail before Lydia dropped by after her meeting, we discussed my wireframe layouts, and selected the layout that we felt was the best balance between our brand and creating something new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s where things got a bit messy in terms of scheduling. I was contacted by Jim Remsik, one of our Directors of Software Services, who works out of the office in Madison with Kelly. He happened to be in the Chicago office for the day and was seeking to sync with me over coffee. He wanted to address a discussion that I had with Kelly the day prior just about my apprenticeship, my professional goals, my perspective on what is happening with a design director or our company’s growing pains, and the type of projects that I would like 8th Light to bring more of into the pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By this point, Kyle had been struggling and frustrated with HubSpot, where he tried calling Kelly via slack for assistance with working in the design system manager. Although Kelly hasn’t touched much of code since she came to 8th Light because she’s been more focused on addressing projects related to visual design, she was still able to help, guide, and instruct Kyle on how to make the changes. She helped Kyle solve the problem in a reasonable timeframe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the last task, which was coding the selected wireframe that me, Lydia, and Kyle agreed upon, I had interrupted my pairing session to grab coffee and have a discussion with Jim Remsik. By the time that I returned, Kyle and I had just enough time to start incorporating the header of the wireframe that I created but not to complete the section entirely because the task did not have a hard deadline or of high priority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/main&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Pairing Tour — Day 04</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/gina-blog/2019/02/21/post18.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/gina-blog/2019/02/21/post18.html</id>
    <published>2019-02-20T18:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2020-02-01T13:28:38-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;main class="blogposts__container"&gt;
  &lt;header class="header-main"&gt;
    &lt;h1&gt;Pairing Tour — Day 04&lt;/h1&gt;
    &lt;time datetime="2019-02-21"&gt;February 21, 2019&lt;/time&gt;
  &lt;/header&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I paired with Kelly Rauwerdink, a talented illustrator, designer, and art director at 8th Light. I joined her morning standup with Julia Murray, UX designer and researcher. Shortly after our morning standup, the three of us along with Chris Peak regrouped to join a meeting with our client to present usability testing research done by Julia with help from Nadia, as well as the low-fidelity wireframes she had created for the usability testing. The client responded well and seemed excited to see how these wireframes would come to life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Directly following standup, Kelly and I began pairing remotely via video chat. Aside from the fact that our pairing was done remotely, what made pairing with Kelly drastically different from my other pairings was that I spent the entire day giving live feedback on color distribution, suggestions for layout, and instructing her in general Sketch app “etiquette” (i.e. the importance of naming layers, dynamic symbols, overrides, leading for the web, etc.) because she recently learned and picked up the Sketch workflow. This pairing was the closest opportunity that I have ever had to do anything art direction related in a professional environment that involved branding. It was exciting, refreshing, and challenging to direct, offer guidance, and give constructive feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although collaborating that closely for long periods of time can be draining, I felt as though we both needed it. For me, it was really enjoyable getting to know Kelly on a more personal level, her working processes with designing, how she interacts with clients, and practicing my communication and critiquing skills. For Kelly, I think that she shared my enjoyment in getting to know each other but also just generally getting to spend time more closely with a (future, hopefully) design team member, especially since she is remote 98% of the time due to working out of our office in Madison.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Together we worked on addressing some edits that the ad agency team emailed over the night prior into that morning, some of which in my opinion, were too literal. Due to the ad agency team’s understanding of what a brand style guide is and thinking that illustrations are a reflection of a “style guide,” they pushed for not using black and white anywhere in the design. The strangeness in their preference is that every brand style guide uses black and white by default because there should always be black and white versions for the logo in addition to considering the flexibility in text usage for readability and legibility purposes against colored or non-colored backgrounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another issue was how we were managing our client’s expectations along with the brand reputation itself. The client was looking forward to seeing Julia’s wireframes come to life, whereas the design that the ad agency team pushed for Kelly to work with looked completely different, not to mention oversimplified where it did not address some of the wants/needs of the users according to the research she encountered in usability testing. Kelly had to make two designs for the homepage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regarding the brand reputation, the ad agency team was too focused on incorporating the vibrant, radiating color palette from the illustrations. Although it’s true that illustrations do and should make use of what the brand color palette is, the color palettes that illustrations use do not necessarily always consider accessibility and do not always transition smoothly for the web. Also, typically the brand style guide is established before the illustrations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, by not considering accessibility, what message would we be sending out to our client’s target audience? Aside from the fact that inaccessible websites are illegal, in a sense it communicates that those with disabilities and impairments do not matter. Additionally, in the larger scheme of our client’s goals, how does this accomplish being more diverse and inclusive?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kelly and I worked together under these difficult circumstances trying to address the issues that the ad agency team had with her designs (also, trying hard not to cringe every step of the way with addressing their edits). We ended up with something we were content with, where we ended the day with an email to the ad agency team for approval.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/main&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Pairing Tour — Day 03</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/gina-blog/2019/02/20/post17.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/gina-blog/2019/02/20/post17.html</id>
    <published>2019-02-19T18:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2020-02-01T13:28:38-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;main class="blogposts__container"&gt;
  &lt;header class="header-main"&gt;
    &lt;h1&gt;Pairing Tour — Day 03&lt;/h1&gt;
    &lt;time datetime="2019-02-20"&gt;February 20, 2019&lt;/time&gt;
  &lt;/header&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I paired with Chris Peak, a senior designer and developer at 8th Light, who is also a talented photographer on the side (even though he thinks of himself as more of an “enthusiast”). I started the day with a code review of a pull request that I made using the basis of my wireframes from my last project for the Chicago Symphony Orchestra for code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started tinkering with the navigation to see what it would look like in responsive web design. One of the first nuggets of advice that Chris gave me was basically “less is more.” He explained how I should have started my code with mobile first. Another interesting approach that Chris uses in his working process is making components responsive as you go, tackling one by one as opposed to fully designing for one screen type throughout, then going back to make it all responsive on the other sizes, and so forth. Working with Chris was extremely helpful. He also made sure to ask what editor I was comfortable working in, which I really appreciated. He normally uses Vim, which is harder from what I’ve been told.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chris also taught me something new, which was a little javascript and jquery to do something very simple: toggle the navigation button between the icon and the dropdown. After reviewing my code, we transitioned into a recent request that came in from our CEO, which did not have too much context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was some kind of virtual reality platform or desktop app that could be used to track their inventory over the course of days, weeks, and months on the shelves. The team that Chris was working on said that the request was for UI design but only for a smaller component: a play/reverse feature for the virtual video model with some dropdown menus to look at intervals or timelines over the course of different periods. The app was lacking context and had a few UX problems, such as incorporating controls in a menu dropdown or repeating elements that are related but could mean/lead to something entirely different. Instead of actually designing anything, we wrote a list of some of these questions/concerns. I also had a bit of an opportunity to show Chris how to use Sketch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then paired on another one of his projects, which is an internal one for advertising future company tech related conferences. He showed me some of his logo development process, as well as the logo that he finally got approved. He began brainstorming a list of adjectives, where we had a discussion about past conferences that Chris has attended and what he enjoyed about them to help generate words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, following this pairing we had a meeting that overlapped with other members of the design team, Kelly Rauwerdink and Julia Murray, because Chris would be working on coding the site for their pro bono client project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/main&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
