<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2019-02-22T18:00:00-06:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Pairing Tour — Day 06</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/gina-blog/2019/02/23/post20.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/gina-blog/2019/02/23/post20.html</id>
    <published>2019-02-22T18:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2019-02-25T16:45:40-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;main class="blogposts__container"&gt;
  &lt;header class="header-main"&gt;
    &lt;h1&gt;Pairing Tour — Day 06&lt;/h1&gt;
    &lt;time datetime="2019-02-22"&gt;February 23, 2019&lt;/time&gt;
  &lt;/header&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I paired with Kevin Zolkiewicz, a designer at 8th Light who also happens to be a talented front-end developer. Kevin began our pairing day by introducing me to a merge conflict (thanks, Kevin). He and Alexa Albanese, another designer here at 8th Light, had been working on the same client for a few months now. With this client, they were working with contractors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The merge conflict that he showed me was from one of the contractors on the project, Jeneve, who focused on laying out some of the foundations of the front-end development to tackle more of the back-end. Kevin explained more about the code workflow, JavaScript and token, and React. He explained how they are pulling information from the database (back-end) to produce how the website is displayed using the awesome powers and convenience of React (front-end). He walked me through the merge conflict and resolved it by keeping both of the conflicts because they were lines of code created by him and Jeneve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was interesting to see how everything that I have learned during my apprenticeship applies in real-world context. Kevin explained how sites these days are actually now fully built using JavaScript as opposed to just HTML/CSS. The similarities and overlap between those languages was interesting because some of what I saw in the JavaScript file was very similar to using tokens or mixins in Sass, however, far more advanced than I would ever have to deal with or touch as a designer. He let me try using tokens and writing in the language a little before switching back over to figuring out how he would refactor some of Jeneve's rough layout of code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, we split up for part of our pairing. Reason being was because the implementation wasn't too engaging since I'm not familiar with the language he's working in.  Plus, it would give Kevin an opportunity to finish up his work, so that we could pair on something else. I had suggested that I could use some of this time to catch up on writing blog posts about my pairing tours since I was three days behind in terms of writing, so it worked out! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After refactoring some of Jeneve's code to be more manageable, Kevin went over the basics of ITSCSS and an introduction to programming by teaching me some basic JavaScript terminology: variables (booleans and strings), loops, conditionals, functions, operators, and briefly went over arrays. He figured that it would be nice just to help me familiarize with the language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/main&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Pairing Tour — Day 05</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/gina-blog/2019/02/22/post19.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/gina-blog/2019/02/22/post19.html</id>
    <published>2019-02-21T18:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2019-02-25T16:45:42-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;main class="blogposts__container"&gt;
  &lt;header class="header-main"&gt;
    &lt;h1&gt;Pairing Tour — Day 05&lt;/h1&gt;
    &lt;time datetime="2019-02-22"&gt;February 22, 2019&lt;/time&gt;
  &lt;/header&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I paired with Kyle Sparks, who is Communications Manager here at 8th Light. Kyle generally works on writing for internal requests, such as for proposals and presentations. He’s also very familiar with the GitHub workflow, along with coding skills in HTML, CSS, Ruby, and yaml.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pairing with Kyle is always enjoyable because he completes work with a sense of humor, lightheartedness, and professionalism. He came prepared this morning with a list of three things that he had coordinated on with Lydia Lindenberg, our Marketing Manager:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol class="blogpost--ol-indent"&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fix a simple social media link issue for 8th Light’s upcoming events on our website, so that when a site visitor clicked on “Facebook” or “Twitter,” they would be redirected to our company’s social accounts.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;Figure out possible layouts to address a specific section of our company’s homepage that displayed our services. According to research, users were unclear about what exactly our company does, despite having a section dedicated to what we do.&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;Add a section with a button on the company’s main blockchain services page that would direct users to the field guide download page.&lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li&gt;An additional but not absolutely necessary task that Kyle wanted to tackle was our company’s email design for the weekly bytes. We glazed over this point only as an introduction to some future work that Kyle might need help with.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kyle began our pairing by introducing me to the 8th Light codebase, which was way more familiar and manageable than the HubSpot workflow. He was careful and conscious about mansplaining, which I really appreciated, and made sure to let me know that I could interrupt him if I already knew something. He instructed me on some commands in terminal for cloning the repository and opening up in my text editor of choice: Visual Studio Code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were quick to fix the link issue and then moved on to addressing possible layouts for the section of the company’s homepage that would focus on our selling points. I worked in Sketch, ensuring to manage expectations and state that I cannot design and code at the same time. I created a few different wireframe layouts, attempting to stay consistent with our brand’s (informal) website style guide and referencing with Kyle what the other landing page headers look like. He seemed excited and interested in learning Sketch, where I suggested that I could teach him one of these days during waza, a brand specific term at our company that refers to a dedicated time slot to professional development, learning new skills, and/or working on side projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I finished the possible layouts in Sketch, we reached out to Lydia to ask for her feedback. At the time, she was in a meeting, so we then moved onto another task, which was creating the section with the button for the blockchain services landing page. Although this seemed simple, the challenge came with using the HubSpot interface, where related things feel so disconnected across the site in terms of the UX. The basic thing that Kyle and I had accomplished was placing the section and button underneath the header, but the problem was that the background color of that section was purple—so was the header.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem was trying to change that background to the lightest shade of gray in our style guide and change the text to be a darker shade of gray to match the rest of the brand. We had tackled it for roughly a half hour to no avail before Lydia dropped by after her meeting, we discussed my wireframe layouts, and selected the layout that we felt was the best balance between our brand and creating something new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s where things got a bit messy in terms of scheduling. I was contacted by Jim Remsik, one of our Directors of Software Services, who works out of the office in Madison with Kelly. He happened to be in the Chicago office for the day and was seeking to sync with me over coffee. He wanted to address a discussion that I had with Kelly the day prior just about my apprenticeship, my professional goals, my perspective on what is happening with a design director or our company’s growing pains, and the type of projects that I would like 8th Light to bring more of into the pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By this point, Kyle had been struggling and frustrated with HubSpot, where he tried calling Kelly via slack for assistance with working in the design system manager. Although Kelly hasn’t touched much of code since she came to 8th Light because she’s been more focused on addressing projects related to visual design, she was still able to help, guide, and instruct Kyle on how to make the changes. She helped Kyle solve the problem in a reasonable timeframe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the last task, which was coding the selected wireframe that me, Lydia, and Kyle agreed upon, I had interrupted my pairing session to grab coffee and have a discussion with Jim Remsik. By the time that I returned, Kyle and I had just enough time to start incorporating the header of the wireframe that I created but not to complete the section entirely because the task did not have a hard deadline or of high priority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/main&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Pairing Tour — Day 04</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/gina-blog/2019/02/21/post18.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/gina-blog/2019/02/21/post18.html</id>
    <published>2019-02-20T18:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2019-02-25T16:35:59-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;main class="blogposts__container"&gt;
  &lt;header class="header-main"&gt;
    &lt;h1&gt;Pairing Tour — Day 04&lt;/h1&gt;
    &lt;time datetime="2019-02-21"&gt;February 21, 2019&lt;/time&gt;
  &lt;/header&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I paired with Kelly Rauwerdink, a talented illustrator, designer, and art director at 8th Light. I joined her morning standup with Julia Murray, UX designer and researcher. Shortly after our morning standup, the three of us along with Chris Peak regrouped to join a meeting with our client to present usability testing research done by Julia with help from Nadia, as well as the low-fidelity wireframes she had created for the usability testing. The client responded well and seemed excited to see how these wireframes would come to life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Directly following standup, Kelly and I began pairing remotely via video chat. Aside from the fact that our pairing was done remotely, what made pairing with Kelly drastically different from my other pairings was that I spent the entire day giving live feedback on color distribution, suggestions for layout, and instructing her in general Sketch app “etiquette” (i.e. the importance of naming layers, dynamic symbols, overrides, leading for the web, etc.) because she recently learned and picked up the Sketch workflow. This pairing was the closest opportunity that I have ever had to do anything art direction related in a professional environment that involved branding. It was exciting, refreshing, and challenging to direct, offer guidance, and give constructive feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although collaborating that closely for long periods of time can be draining, I felt as though we both needed it. For me, it was really enjoyable getting to know Kelly on a more personal level, her working processes with designing, how she interacts with clients, and practicing my communication and critiquing skills. For Kelly, I think that she shared my enjoyment in getting to know each other but also just generally getting to spend time more closely with a (future, hopefully) design team member, especially since she is remote 98% of the time due to working out of our office in Madison.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Together we worked on addressing some edits that the ad agency team emailed over the night prior into that morning, some of which in my opinion, were too literal. Due to the ad agency team’s understanding of what a brand style guide is and thinking that illustrations are a reflection of a “style guide,” they pushed for not using black and white anywhere in the design. The strangeness in their preference is that every brand style guide uses black and white by default because there should always be black and white versions for the logo in addition to considering the flexibility in text usage for readability and legibility purposes against colored or non-colored backgrounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another issue was how we were managing our client’s expectations along with the brand reputation itself. The client was looking forward to seeing Julia’s wireframes come to life, whereas the design that the ad agency team pushed for Kelly to work with looked completely different, not to mention oversimplified where it did not address some of the wants/needs of the users according to the research she encountered in usability testing. Kelly had to make two designs for the homepage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regarding the brand reputation, the ad agency team was too focused on incorporating the vibrant, radiating color palette from the illustrations. Although it’s true that illustrations do and should make use of what the brand color palette is, the color palettes that illustrations use do not necessarily always consider accessibility and do not always transition smoothly for the web. Also, typically the brand style guide is established before the illustrations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, by not considering accessibility, what message would we be sending out to our client’s target audience? Aside from the fact that inaccessible websites are illegal, in a sense it communicates that those with disabilities and impairments do not matter. Additionally, in the larger scheme of our client’s goals, how does this accomplish being more diverse and inclusive?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kelly and I worked together under these difficult circumstances trying to address the issues that the ad agency team had with her designs (also, trying hard not to cringe every step of the way with addressing their edits). We ended up with something we were content with, where we ended the day with an email to the ad agency team for approval.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/main&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Pairing Tour — Day 03</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/gina-blog/2019/02/20/post17.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/gina-blog/2019/02/20/post17.html</id>
    <published>2019-02-19T18:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2019-02-25T16:31:25-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;main class="blogposts__container"&gt;
  &lt;header class="header-main"&gt;
    &lt;h1&gt;Pairing Tour — Day 03&lt;/h1&gt;
    &lt;time datetime="2019-02-20"&gt;February 20, 2019&lt;/time&gt;
  &lt;/header&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I paired with Chris Peak, a senior designer and developer at 8th Light, who is also a talented photographer on the side (even though he thinks of himself as more of an “enthusiast”). I started the day with a code review of a pull request that I made using the basis of my wireframes from my last project for the Chicago Symphony Orchestra for code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started tinkering with the navigation to see what it would look like in responsive web design. One of the first nuggets of advice that Chris gave me was basically “less is more.” He explained how I should have started my code with mobile first. Another interesting approach that Chris uses in his working process is making components responsive as you go, tackling one by one as opposed to fully designing for one screen type throughout, then going back to make it all responsive on the other sizes, and so forth. Working with Chris was extremely helpful. He also made sure to ask what editor I was comfortable working in, which I really appreciated. He normally uses Vim, which is harder from what I’ve been told.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chris also taught me something new, which was a little javascript and jquery to do something very simple: toggle the navigation button between the icon and the dropdown. After reviewing my code, we transitioned into a recent request that came in from our CEO, which did not have too much context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was some kind of virtual reality platform or desktop app that could be used to track their inventory over the course of days, weeks, and months on the shelves. The team that Chris was working on said that the request was for UI design but only for a smaller component: a play/reverse feature for the virtual video model with some dropdown menus to look at intervals or timelines over the course of different periods. The app was lacking context and had a few UX problems, such as incorporating controls in a menu dropdown or repeating elements that are related but could mean/lead to something entirely different. Instead of actually designing anything, we wrote a list of some of these questions/concerns. I also had a bit of an opportunity to show Chris how to use Sketch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then paired on another one of his projects, which is an internal one for advertising future company tech related conferences. He showed me some of his logo development process, as well as the logo that he finally got approved. He began brainstorming a list of adjectives, where we had a discussion about past conferences that Chris has attended and what he enjoyed about them to help generate words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, following this pairing we had a meeting that overlapped with other members of the design team, Kelly Rauwerdink and Julia Murray, because Chris would be working on coding the site for their pro bono client project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/main&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Pairing Tour — Day 02</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/gina-blog/2019/02/19/post16.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/gina-blog/2019/02/19/post16.html</id>
    <published>2019-02-18T18:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2019-02-25T16:31:30-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;main class="blogposts__container"&gt;
  &lt;header class="header-main"&gt;
    &lt;h1&gt;Pairing Tour — Day 02&lt;/h1&gt;
    &lt;time datetime="2019-02-19"&gt;February 19, 2019&lt;/time&gt;
  &lt;/header&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I paired with Julia Murray, another member of the design team at 8th Light that focuses on UX design and research. Julia had been working on a client account that was pro bono for a women-focused organization with other members of our design team, Kelly Rauwerdink &lt;a href="/2019/02/18/post15.html"&gt;(check out Kelly's bio here)&lt;/a&gt; and Nadia Doutcheva, a college graduate student who is currently interning at 8th Light and doing UX research. On this project, Nadia focused on making a research report on some usability testing that she and Julia had conducted the week prior. Unfortunately, Nadia was not present for my pairing tour with Julia due to attending to her coursework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our pairing began with a morning standup between me, Julia, and Kelly discussing the current status of the client account that they are on. In addition to working with the organization itself, Julia and Kelly had struggled with collaborating with a team from a major ad agency and an illustrator in trying to encourage the organization’s target audience to take action for women’s advocacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From my understanding, the illustrator had been working with the organization’s branding and tone for awhile. However, due to not having a strong design background, there were no standardized brand guidelines for logo usage, typography, color usage, etc. The illustrator is still on the account creating content but eventually plans to leave to pursue projects or work elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although working with the ad agency team sounded promising, it turned out that their team of creatives were not actually designers. They were project managers and copywriters, individuals who focused more on strategy than on visual and UI/UX design. One of the members was a previous employee at Julia and Kelly’s current client, had pursued a job at this ad agency, and was still continuing to work with this client to show support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Immediately following standup, Julia debriefed me on the user research and usability testing that she and Nadia collaborated on. After her explanation, I worked on designing a presentation to better visualize the findings that she and Nadia had collected to help make it feel more branded. After completing this task, getting some feedback and iterating, I attended a design review meeting with the ad agency team. And let me just say, it did not go well..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We learned that the ad agency team misunderstood how branding translates into UI design. They were under the impression that a brand style guide, which is normally used for print, is equivalent to a UI design system. Although branding is where visual design and UI design meet, they are still extremely different in terms of the audiences and the medium itself with which the consumer interacts: the tangible vs. the digital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although branding can go into aspects of the digital space, it only scratches the surface in terms of accessibility and the standardization of components, modules, and patterns in UI experienced across the web. The ad agency team criticized Kelly’s work, claiming that it was equivalent to “government websites” and that it should incorporate all 6 colors from the illustrations that were made—mind you, that didn’t even account for 8 colors in total because a brand always includes black and white for text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the ad agency team didn’t seem too willing to work with our internal team, despite this being only their second meeting ever with Julia and Kelly. They were not only late to the meeting but joined the meeting more than 10 minutes late all via phone with the exception of one knowing that it was a design review to see the work Kelly had done. They also had the nerve to ask her to email the wireframe mockups over instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After this difficult meeting, I began working on a page with deeply nested information that Julia had been attempting to organize in a more digestible manner. However, since the page was a timeline of the organization’s accomplishments and the client was still working on changing copy, there was still too much information to work with. The timeline was organized by decade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside from the information overload, the thought of incorporating 6 visually radiating colors that do not pair well together, worrying about responsive design especially for mobile development, and telling a story as requested from the stakeholder herself was a daunting process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, I managed to figure out a way to make it work while using the colors as subtler accent colors and focusing on the great historical photos that the organization had to aid in telling their story. I shared it with Julia for feedback, along with Kelly for her reference and to help inspire some elements for UI design, which made me really happy to know that I contributed something that was actually useful for my teammates!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/main&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Pairing Tour — Day 01</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/gina-blog/2019/02/18/post15.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/gina-blog/2019/02/18/post15.html</id>
    <published>2019-02-17T18:00:00-06:00</published>
    <updated>2019-02-25T16:29:09-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;main class="blogposts__container"&gt;
  &lt;header class="header-main"&gt;
    &lt;h1&gt;Pairing Tour — Day 01&lt;/h1&gt;
    &lt;time datetime="2019-02-18"&gt;February 18, 2019&lt;/time&gt;
  &lt;/header&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today officially marks the start of my pairing tours! This week is primarily dedicated to pairing with members of the design team at 8th Light. Since the design team works together—more often than not—on certain projects according to client need, there will be an overlap of working with other design team members simultaneously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I paired with Alexa Albanese, who has been at 8th Light for the past two years now specializing in UX design and research. Additionally, I worked with two other members of the design team: Kevin Zolk and Kelly Rauwerdink. For context, here’s a quick background on each member:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kevin Zolk&lt;/strong&gt; is a Chicago based senior designer and developer, who likes to focus primarily on interaction design but also happens to be a talented visual designer and front-end developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kelly Rauwerdink&lt;/strong&gt; is a Madison based illustrator, art director, and designer specializing in branding. She is originally from a different company called Adorable. When 8th Light acquired Adorable, Kelly became a part of the team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Alexa and I paired on a client account that she, Kevin, and Kelly have been on for some time now (translation: months) tackling visual design (branding), UI design, and soon, implementation into code. The account has two stakeholders who are seeking to create a desktop app for issuers, investors, and advisors to help ease the stress and confusion of the overall investing process. However, the ride’s been rocky due to the complexity of the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The investing app involves various third parties that communicate between each other: banks, tax documents, and entities that update the stakeholders on where their investors are in the process, all the while communicating directly with the investors accessing the app. Unfortunately, I knew long before pairing with them that Kevin, Alexa, and Kelly had faced difficulties with their internal working dynamics as a team and the clients themselves. Earlier in the process, our team learned quickly that one of the stakeholders was particular about the visual design and UI design. It sounded as though he struggled to focus on the bigger picture and became fixated on smaller details whenever given the opportunity to give feedback. Witnessing our team in distress, made me wonder just how much I could actually contribute or help with their working processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Briefly before our pairing session, Alexa reviewed her work with Kevin, where he provided some constructive feedback and a list of things that he felt she and I could tackle together. Amongst the items on that list that we tackled were: typography spacing, three folder elements, progress bar, invitations bar, and color.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TYPOGRAPHY SPACING&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; 
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was just to make the spacing consistent between different elements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THREE FOLDER ELEMENTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These components were similar to icons except they contained text that defined which documents needed action or how many people were using the desktop app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PROGRESS BAR&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This component showed where the investors are in the overall process of investing. It showed the different steps, along with subtasks to accomplish those steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;INVITATIONS BAR&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This bar was basically a visual graph of the database. The graph would show how many invitations were pending, how many are in each step of the process, and which ones were already completed. This bar would constantly change according to what is in the database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;COLOR PALETTE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kevin proposed incorporating a gold color because there was not enough contrast between the different shades of blue.
Although this client did not happen to like the addition of gold amongst the other shades of blue, they really liked our solution for the Invitations Bar, as it would successfully account for the constantly changing information on their database. For example, what happens when there’s 1 deal in process vs. having 100 deals in process?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to this client, I attended a development demo with Alexa’s other client, a company selling a phone app for grocery deliveries. This one was not as exciting but definitely important and useful in getting familiarized with the development team working processes at 8th Light. I learned that they use Jira, a point system for time estimation, and that they separate their work into stories. From my understanding, stories refer to breaking the work up into more manageable chunks to divide it between the development team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/main&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
